(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-29T10:06:58.508195",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
みんな、応援してくれてありがとう！
Everyone, thank you so much!
やったー！うわぁ！
Yatta! Woo-hoo!
銀河の隅で
In a corner of the Milky Way,
惑星はグルグル回る
the planets turn, going round and round.
電波の記録
A radio wave recording,
エコが返ってきた
an echo returned.
これで何回だ？
How many times does this make it?
遠くの宇宙で
In the distant cosmos,
あなたに恋をしたんだ
I fell in love with you.
届かないこと
Even though I understand that
理解しているのに
I won't reach...
あーあなたに逢いたいなって
"Ah, I wanna meet you,"
気持ちがループ、ループする
my feelings loop, they loop.
頭がどうにかなりそうだ
I feel like I'm gonna lose it,
それ以外交わせない
I can't exchange anything else.
あーいますぐ逢いたいなって
"Ah, I wanna meet you right now,"
来る日もループ、ループする
the coming days loop too, they loop.
この周回軌道上にあなたがいなくても
Even if you're not on this orbit,
そこに大体、愛があるだけ
there, generally, is only love.
あーいますぐ逢いたいなって
"Ah, I wanna meet you right now,"
来る日もループ、ループする
the coming days loop too, they loop.
この周回軌道上にあなたがいなくても
Even if you're not on this orbit,
それ以外想えない
I can't think of anything else.
そこに大体、愛があるだけ
There, generally, is only love.
みんな、応援してくれてありがとう！
Everyone, thank you so much!
声を辿って 何光年だ
Following your voice, how many light years has it been?
延長線に消えていく
Disappearing away into the extension.
このままパッと忘れられたら
If I could forget about it, just like that,
楽だろうな
I'm sure it would be a lot easier.
触れられないのに
Even though I can't touch you,
見えてしまって
I end up seeing you.
どうしようもないや
It just can't be helped.
近くて遠いあなただ
It's you, so close, yet so far.
理解しているよ
I understand that,
あーそれでも逢いたいなって
nevertheless, I wanna meet you...
何度もループ、ループする
I loop around many, many times.
心があなたで鳴っている
My heart is crying with you,
それだけが確かだ
that alone is certain.
それだけでいいよ。
That alone is all I need.
ああ、星が周るように
Ah, just as the stars turn,
ぼくらはずっとループする
we keep on looping forever.
想いが軌道を描いている
My feelings are drawing an orbit,
あなただけを追うよ
only chasing after you.
あーいますぐ逢いたいなって
"Ah, I wanna meet you right now,"
命がループ、ループする
my life loops around, it loops.
この周回軌道上にあなたがいなくても
Even if you're not on this orbit,
それ以外想えない
I can't think of anything else.
そこに大体、愛があるだけ
There, generally, is only love.
というわけでみなさんこんにちは！ときのそらです！
And that's why... Hello everyone, I'm Tokino Sora!
お水もらった
I got some water.
ときのそら4周年記念配信に皆さん来てくれてありがとうございます。
Thank you everyone for coming to my 4th anniversary stream!
みて！あんきもと一しょに動いたよ！あんきも、
Look! Ankimo moved with me! Ankimo,
あんきも！
Ankimo!
あんきもの舞台に立ったよ！いぇい！
I stood on Ankimo's stage! Yay!
やっぱかわいい。かわいいけど
So cute. Cute, but...
今日は私が主役！あんきものデビュー今日じゃないからね！
Today I'm the main star! Today isn't Ankimo's debut, you know!
と、弱気で...。久しぶりにね、あんきもと私でちょっとね、歌をうたうことができて、
And, feeling timid... For the first time in a while, Ankimo and I were able to sing a song together,
久しぶりにこのステージに立つことができて、とっても嬉しいです！
and stand on this stage for the first time in a while, I'm so happy!
みんな、今日は盛り上がっていきましょう！
Everyone, let's get hyped up today!
そしてそして、今日なんですが...。今日なんですが...みんな素敵なゲスト呼んでるからね！
And, and, today... Today... I'm calling wonderful guests, you know!
早くゲストのみんなにも会いたいって思わない？思わない？
Don't you want to meet all the guests soon? Don't you think so?
私は思います。んと、弱気で...ここからはですね、ゲストのみんなと一緒に、おひとりおひとりデュエットとかやっていけたらいいなって思ってます。
I think so. Um, timidly... From here on, I'd like to do duets one by one with all the guests.
わためと一緒に歌いたいと思います！その曲はこちら、メランコリック！
I'd like to sing together with Watame! That song is, Melancholic!
全然つかまえないきみのこと 全然知らないうちに
I can't figure you out at all, and before I even knew anything,
ココロ奪われるなんてこと あるはずないでしょ
there's no way my heart would be stolen like that.
メランコリック！
Melancholic!
それは無愛想な笑顔だったり
Whether it's an aloof smile,
それは日曜日の日暮れだったり
or dusk on a Sunday,
それはテスト∞(ばっか)の期間だったり
or a period full of nothing but exams,
それはきみという名のメランコミニスト。
or a melancholinist called you.
手当り次第強気でぶつかっても なににも手には残らないって思い込んでる
I'm convinced that blindly confronting things with bravado leaves me with nothing in the end.
ちょっとくらいの勇気にだって ちっちゃくなってふさぎ込んでるわたしだから
Because whenever I need just a little courage, I shrink away and lock myself up.
全然つかまえないきみのこと 全然知らないうちに ココロ奪われる
I can't figure you out at all, and before I even knew it, my heart is stolen—
なんてこと あるはずないでしょ
no, there's no way that could happen!
全然気づかないきみのこと 全然知らない 知らないもんだね
You don't notice anything at all, so I don't know a thing about you.
「ねえねえ」じゃないわ この笑顔 また眠れないでしょ
Don't "hey hey" me, or I won't be able to sleep again.
明日も同じわたしがいるのかな
I wonder if I'll still be the same me tomorrow—
無愛想で無口なままの 可愛くないやつ
a grumpy, taciturn, unlikable girl.
あの夢にきみが出てきたときから 素直じゃないのって
Ever since you appeared in that dream of mine, I haven't been able to be honest.
全然つかまえないきみのこと 全然知らないうちに
I can't figure you out at all, and before I even knew it,
ココロ奪おうとしてたのはわたしのほうもそう
I was the one trying to steal your heart too—
そういうじかんのおくれだいいとおいしのメランコリー
that's the kind of phase I'm in, drowning in this sweet melancholy.
全然つかめないきみのこと
I don't get you at all
全然しらないうちに
before I even knew it.
はい、というわけで一緒に歌いましたゲストは角巻わため、ウォ、わためぇ！
Yes, so our guest who sang with us today is Tsunomaki Watame—whoa, Watame!
お疲れ様です！
Great job!
こんばんは、どどどどどどどどど
Good evening, do-do-do-do-do-do-do-do-do
いや、最後のとこさ、ハート1人でやってたかと思ったらさ、最後の最後やったよ！
Hey, at the very end, I thought I was doing the heart alone, but you did it right at the end!
あれー？やったよー！
Huh? I did it!
あ、やってくれた？ 届かないけど
Oh, you did it? Though it didn't reach you.
いやー、来てくれてありがとう！いや、こっちこそ呼んでくれてありがとう！
Man, thank you for coming! No, thank you so much for inviting me!
なんかね、せっかくの4周年だから誰かと一緒に歌いたいなと思って
Well, since it's the 4th anniversary, I wanted to sing together with someone.
わぁ、嬉しい！呼んでくれて！ねえ！
Yay, I'm so happy you invited me! Right!
今度はあれもやろうね、ゲームも！ゲーム？あっ、あれ？
Next time let's play games too! Games? Ah, what?
探検？そう、探検ね！
Expedition? Yeah, exploration!
そう！さっきね、そう、それもね、待ってる間に、そう！
Yeah! Earlier, yeah, while waiting for that, yeah!
ああ、わため、今度さって、言ったら、同じて、同じタイミングでね、そう探検！みたいな
Ah, Watame, when I said "next time," we said "exploration!" at the exact same time like that.
同じことよーとしてたってね！おーってなって心がね通じ合ってるのがね、通じ合ってるんだね！
We were trying to do the exact same thing! We were like "Whoa," and our hearts connected! We understand each other!
わかりましたんですね。ねえ、ねえ、ねえ。
I see. Right, right, right.
今回ね、メランコリックを一緒に歌ってもらったんですけど、
This time, we sang "Melancholic" together,
このメランコリックは、なんか、私も結構初期の頃に歌わせて頂いてる曲で、
and "Melancholic" is a song I sang quite early on,
わためもね、素敵なアレンジで歌っていたのを観ていたので、こう一緒に歌えたら嬉しいなと思って選んだ！
and I saw Watame singing it with a lovely arrangement, so I chose it hoping it'd be fun to sing together!
嬉しいでーす！ねえ！それにさ、歌ってみたも聴いてるよ！
I'm so happy! Right! Also, I've listened to your cover too!
本当に？ うん！
Really? Yeah!
恥ずかしいな、おい！
That's embarrassing, hey!
いや、だからずっと、わためと一緒に歌いたくって、
I've always wanted to sing with Watame,
歌いたかった！憧れの先輩だし、緊張したでしょ、憧れてもらえるって、うわっ！
I wanted to! You're an admired senior—were you nervous being looked up to? Whoa!
ちょっとびっくりしちゃった。緊張してんの？本当に？
I was a bit startled. Are you nervous? Really?
さっきまで走り回ってたのに！
Even though you were running around just a moment ago!
ドキドキなったよ！
My heart was pounding!
本当に？で、リハーサルでもね、2人でね、すごい何度もやったもんね！やった！ぎりぎりまでやった！
Really? And during rehearsal we practiced it so many times together! We did! We did it right up to the limit!
そう、ぎりぎりまでね、もう1回、もう1回って言って。
Yeah, right up to the limit, saying "one more time, one more time."
ありがとうございましたね。
Thank you very much.
ねぇ、わためこそありがとうございます。
Right, Watame, thank you so much.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
また、今度一緒に歌ってくれますか？
Will you sing together with me again next time?
もちろん！やったー、これでね！
Of course! Yay, with this!
いや、こちらこそ！お願いします。ちょ、ちょ、やめてよ、やめてよ！
No, thank you! Please. Wait, wait, stop it, stop it!
お願いします！いや、いや、こちらこそ本当に！あ、いいんです。正座なんてなんか。
Please! No, no, really! Ah, it's fine. Sitting seiza like that...
これが床か。床になっちゃったね。
So this is the floor. It became the floor.
床になる、はまたね、別のの今笑ってますけどもね、にやにやしてますけどね。
Becoming the floor... well, we're laughing about something else, grinning and smiling.
というわけで、まだまだゲストはいるので、次のゲストさんにいこうかなと思います。
So, we still have more guests, so I think we'll move on to the next guest.
わため、ありがとう！
Watame, thank you!
わため、ありがとう！また後でね！
Watame, thank you! See you later!
また後でね！
See you later!
はい、というわけで次の曲に行きましょう。次は星街すいせいちゃんと打ち上げ花火。
Right, so let's move on to the next song. Next is Hoshimachi Suisei-chan with "Uchiage Hanabi."
あの日見わたした渚 今も思い出すんだ
The shore we looked out over that day, I still remember it now.
砂の上に刻んだ言葉 君の後ろ姿
Words engraved on the sand, your silhouette.
寄り添う波が足元をよぎり、何かをさらう
The waves coming and going against my feet, washing something away.
夕凪の中日暮れだけが通り過ぎていく
In the evening's calmness, only the twilight passes through.
パッと光って咲いた花火を見ていた
Shining with a bang, we watched the blooming fireworks.
通り過ぎていく
passes through.
パッと光って咲いた
Shining with a bang,
花火を見ていた
we watched the blooming fireworks.
きっとまだ終わらない夏が
Surely summer wasn't over yet,
曖昧な心を解かして繋いだ
unraveling and connecting our uncertain hearts.
この夜が続いて欲しかった
I wanted that night to last forever.
あと何度君と同じ花火を見られるかなって
I wondered how many times I'd see the same fireworks as you,
笑う顔に何ができるだろうか
and what I could do for your smiling face.
傷つくこと喜ぶこと繰り返す波と情動
Pain and joy, repeating waves and emotions,
焦燥 最終列車の音
impatience, the sound of the last train.
何度でも言葉にして君を呼びよろ
I'll call out to you in words again and again,
波間を選び もう一度 もう二度と悲しまずに済むように
choosing the waves, so we never have to feel sad again.
吸うように
breathing it in.
ハッと息を飲めば 消えちゃいそうな光が
With a startled gasp, the fragile light
きっとまだ胸に住んでいた
was surely still dwelling in our chests.
手を伸ばせば触れた 暖かい未来は
The warm future we could touch by reaching out
ひそかに二人で見いていた
had quietly been watching over us both.
パッと花火が
Fireworks suddenly
夜に咲いた
bloomed in the night,
夜に咲いて 静かに消えた
bloomed in the night and quietly faded.
離さないで もう少しだけ
Don't let go, just a little longer,
このままで
just stay like this.
あの日見わたした渚を
The shore we looked out over that day,
今も思い出すんだ
I still remember it now.
砂の上に刻んだ言葉
Words engraved on the sand,
君の後ろ姿
your silhouette.
パッと光って咲いた
Shining with a bang,
花火を見ていた
we watched the blooming fireworks.
きっとまだ終わらない夏が
Surely summer wasn't over yet,
曖昧な心を解かして繋いだ
unraveling and connecting our uncertain hearts.
この夜が続いて欲しかった
I wanted that night to last forever.
ラララ…
La la la...
はいという事で！
And with that!
二人目のゲストはすいちゃん！
Our second guest is Suichan!
はーい、星街すいせいでーす！
Hi! I'm Hoshimachi Suisei!
みなさんこんにちは！お邪魔しまーす！
Hello everyone! Pardon the intrusion!
それではおめでとう！
Congratulations!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
届かなーい！
It didn't reach!
すいちゃんは今日もちいさ…可愛い！
Suichan is so lit— cute today!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
恥ずかしくなっちゃった
I got all embarrassed.
すいちゃんともね、久しぶりに歌いました一緒に。
Suichan and I sang together for the first time in a while.
ね！ね、いつぶりだろうか？
Right? When was the last time?
すいちゃんのライブにゲストで出たとき…
When I appeared as a guest on Suichan's live...
あのときかな、やっぱ最後。1年ぶりぐらい？
That time, I guess. About a year ago?
なんかそんな気がする、割と。
It kind of feels like that, yeah.
結構前だよね、もっと前？
Quite a while ago, even earlier?
うん、そんなに一緒にやってるのか？
Yeah, have we been doing it together that much?
やっても今日ね、呼んでくれて本当に嬉しかった。
Even so, I was really happy you invited me today.
いや、私もきてくれて本当に嬉しく
Yeah, I was really happy you came too.
ね、めちゃくちゃ難しい曲だから、めちゃくちゃね一緒に練習したんだよね。
It's a super difficult song, so we practiced it together a lot.
そう、すごくね、二人でリハもね。
Yeah, we rehearsed a lot together too.
こここうする？とか、はもる？とか話しててんだけど、
We talked about 'should we do this here?' or 'should we harmonize?'
これはそらちゃんの声を活かしたいなと思って私は何もしませんでした。
but I wanted to make the most of Sora-chan's voice, so I didn't do anything.
ゆれて…
swaying...
ちょっと、ちょっと、下、下、ちょっと
Wait, wait, lower, lower, wait.
下、下になって、ちょっと、そう、下、下
Lower, lower, wait, yeah, lower, lower.
三つでもあるのかな？
Are there even three?
水がね、ヒット、ヒット、下、下、下に滑っちゃうな
The water... hits, hits, slips lower and lower.
滑っちゃうな、それは
It slips down, yeah.
うん
Yeah.
そう、もうね、そう、かなり聞いてる、かなり聞いてるって
Yeah, already, yeah, it's really working, really working.
何を？
What is?
あ、そう、まあでも我々2人で歌ってみた動画を
Ah, right, well, we released a video of us singing together.
あ、そうなんだ。そうなんだ
Ah, is that right? That's right.
それはいっぱい聞いてくれてるのかな？
I wonder if people are listening to it a lot?
聞いてくれるさあ！
They're definitely listening!
They're listening!
その時は私がそらちゃんを誘ったんだけど
Back then I invited Sora-chan,
今回はなんとそらちゃんから誘って
but this time, Sora-chan invited me,
いただきまして、あ、嬉しいなと思いながら
and I was so happy, thinking...
すごいね、すぐ解禁
That's amazing, immediate release!
来て、そう、そう、そう
It came out, yeah, yeah, yeah.
このやりたいんだけど、スケジュール教えて、みたいな
Like, "I want to do this, let me know your schedule."
あ、スケジュール次第で、全然きますけど、お見せだよ
Ah, depending on the schedule, I'm totally free, but look at that—
もうすごい、あっさり来るじゃんと思って
I thought, "Wow, it comes so easily!"
やりますって、大体すいちゃんそう、何回やる？やる？みたいな
Like, "We'll do it," Suisei's usually like, "How many times do we do it? Do it?"
ノリがめちゃくちゃいいの
Her vibe is so great!
いや、やる？って
Like, "Wanna do it?"
だから今日も、軽率だけに押して、やる？って
So today too, casually urging, "Wanna do it?"
来ました
It came!
いやでもそういうね、気持ちに来てくれるのがね一番嬉しい
But you know, having someone come with that feeling is the happiest thing.
すごく楽しかった。やっぱそらちゃんと一緒に歌え
It was so fun. Being able to sing together with Sora-chan
るっていうのはね、我々からしたらもうビッグイベントですからね
is, from our perspective, a big event!
ビッグイベントですからね
A big event!
そうだ、そうだよ
That's right, that's right.
なかなか無いことですからね
Because it's a rare occurrence!
確かにね
That's true.
もう4年ですよ、そらちゃん
It's already been 4 years, Sora-chan!
いやもう4年
Yeah, already 4 years.
え、すいちゃんもだから、うん、割と
Eh, Suisei-chan also, well, relatively...
割とでも近いよね
Well, relatively close, right?
近いよね
Close, right?
私が来年の3月で4年だから
I reach 4 years next March, so
そうだよね
That's right.
そう、半年、半いくらいかな
So, half a year... about half a year difference.
あ、半年差か、ぐらいか
Ah, half a year difference, around there.
いやでもさ、そんなに経った感じする？
But you know, does it feel like that much time has passed?
しない！
No!
しないよね、全く
Not at all, right? Not at all.
全然しないよね
Not at all.
そうなんだよ
That's right.
みんなもさ、そうじゃない？あんまりそんなに経った感じないよね、きっと
Isn't it the same for everyone? You probably don't feel like it's been that long, right?
うん、そうかも。初期からね、追ってるそらとものみんなは
Yeah, maybe. The Sora-tomos who have been following from the very beginning
もう4年かって
are probably like, "It's already been 4 years?"
そらちゃん、そんなに経ったんだって
Sora-chan, "Has it really been that long?"
みんなあれじゃない？月日の流れる早さにびっくりしちゃってんじゃないか
Aren't they surprised by the speed at which time flies?
そうかもね
Maybe so.
いやでもさ、やっぱ4年前の一番最初の頃と比べて、今だこんな大きなステージ、環境とかはすごい変わってるけど、なんていうのかな、考え方とか大して変わってないよね
But you know, compared to 4 years ago right at the start, now we have such a big stage and environment has changed a lot, but our mindset and way of thinking haven't really changed much, have they?
うん、そう
Yeah, right.
なんていうのかな、もう考え方とか大して変わってない
What should I say, our mindset hasn't really changed.
そっか、そっか
Is that so, is that so.
なんかね、ずっと、ずっと、なんかこんな感じで、のらりくらりと
Somehow, always, always, just like this, taking it easy,
このままね、10年、20年と続けていければいいなと思うね
hoping we can keep going like this for 10, 20 years.
うん
Yeah.
これからも頑張ってほしい、そらちゃんには
I want you to keep doing your best, Sora-chan.
いや、すいちゃんもでしょ？
Hey, you too, Suisei-chan, right?
いや、私ももちろん頑張りますけども
Well, of course I'll do my best too, but
からも5年目も6年目も7年目も8年目も9年目も、頑張っていってください！
from now on, into the 5th, 6th, 7th, 8th, 9th year, please keep doing your best!
頑張ろう！
Let's do our best!
うん、がんばろう！先輩！
Yeah, let's do our best! Senpai!
先輩！
Senpai!
というわけで、2人目のゲスト、星街すいちゃんでした！
And with that, our second guest was Hoshimachi Suisei-chan!
イエーイ！
Yay!
またねー！
See you later!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
では、次に行きたいんですが、1回お水を飲みます。
Well then, I'd like to move on to the next part, but I'll drink some water first.
はい、というわけで、次はあずきちと一緒に歌を歌っていきます。
Alright, so next, AZKi-chan and I will sing a song together.
これね、2人で歌うのは初めての曲です。
This is the first time the two of us are singing this song together.
ONLY MY RAILGUN!
放て！心に刻んだ夢を
Fire away! The dreams engraved in your heart,
未来さえ置き去りにして
leaving even the future behind.
限界なんて知らない 意味ない！
Knowing no limits, it's meaningless!
この能力が光散らす その先に遥かな想いを
My power scatters light, casting distant feelings beyond.
歩いてきた この道を 振り返ることも
If I can only look back on this path I've walked,
出来ないなら…今ここで全てを壊せる
and cannot... I can destroy it all here and now.
闇に堕ちる街並み 人はどこまで立ち向かえるの？
The streets descend into darkness; how far can people resist?
加速するその痛みから 誰かをきっと守れる
I'm sure I can protect someone from this accelerating pain.
Looking！
Looking!
The blitz loop this planet to search way.
Only my railgun can shoot it.
今すぐ 身体中を 光の速さで 駆け巡った 確かな予感
Right now, a certain premonition raced through my body at the speed of light.
掴め！望むものなら残さず 輝ける自分らしさで
Catch it! If it's your wish, don't leave anything behind with your shining self.
信じてるよ あの日の誓いを
I believe in the vow of that day.
この瞳に光る涙 それさえも強さになるから
Even the tears shining in these eyes will become my strength.
立ち止まると 少しだけ 感じる切なさに
Standing still, I feel a slight pain;
戸惑うことなんて嘘はつけないよ
I cannot lie about being confused.
宙に舞うコインが描く 放物線が決める運命
The parabola drawn by the coin dancing in the sky decides our fate.
打ち出した答えが今日も 私の胸を駆け巡る
The answer I shot out races through my chest again today.
Sparkling！
Sparkling!
The shiny lights awake true desire.
Only my railgun can shoot it.
真っ直ぐ貫いてく とまどうことなく 傷ついても はしりつづける
Piercing straight through without hesitation, I keep running even when hurt.
狙え！凛ときわめる視線は くるいなく闇をきりさく
Ready, aim! My dignified gaze tears through the darkness without a flaw.
迷いなんて吹き飛ばせばいい
Just blow away all your doubts.
この心が叫ぶ限り 誰もひとり邪魔などさせない
As long as my heart cries out, I won't let anyone get in my way alone.
はばかくもうそうのねがい この両手に積み重なっていく
The transient wishes pile up in both my hands,
きりさく闇に見えてくるのは 重く深く切ない記憶
and what appears in the tearing darkness is a heavy, deep, painful memory.
いろあせていく現実に揺振れる 絶望には負けたくない
Swaying in a fading reality, I don't want to lose to despair.
私がいま私であること 胸をはって全てほこれる！
Being who I am right now, I can proudly boast of it all!
Looking！
Looking!
The blitz loop this planet to search way.
Only my railgun can shoot it.
放て！心に刻んだ夢を
Fire away! The dreams engraved in your heart,
未来さえ置き去りにして
Leaving even the future behind!
限界など知らない 意味ない！
Knowing no limits, it's meaningless!
この能力(ちから)が光散らす
This power scatters light,
その先に遥かな想いを
Tracing distant feelings beyond.
歩いてきた この道を
The path I've walked along,
振り返ることしか 出来ないなら…
If I can only look back...
今ここで全てを壊せる
I can destroy everything right here.
闇に墜ちる街並みは
The streets descending into darkness,
人はどこまで立ち向かえるの？
How far can people stand against it?
加速するその痛みから
From that accelerating pain,
誰かをきっと守れるよ
I'm sure I can protect someone.
Looking! The blitz loop this planet to search way.
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it.
今すぐ 身体中を
Right now, through my body,
光の速さで 駆け巡った 確かな予感
A certain premonition raced at the speed of light.
掴め！望むものなら残さず
Catch it! If it's your wish, leave nothing behind,
輝ける自分らしさで
With your shining individuality.
信じてるよ あの日の誓いを
I believe in the vow of that day,
この瞳に光る涙 それさえも強さになるから
Even the tears shining in these eyes become strength.
立ち止まると 少しだけ 感じる切なさに
Standing still, feeling a slight pain,
戸惑う事ないなんて 嘘はつかないよ
I won't lie that I have no hesitation.
穹(そら)に舞うコインが描く
The coin dancing in the sky draws
放物線が決める運命
A parabola that decides our fate,
打ち出した答えが今日も 私の胸を駆け巡る
The answer I struck rushes through my chest today too.
Sparkling! The shiny lights awake true desire.
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it without fail.
迷わずに貫いてく
Pressing forward without hesitation,
戸惑うことなく
Without any doubt,
傷付いても走り続ける
Keeping on running even if hurt.
狙え！凛と輝く視線は
Aim! The dignified, shining gaze
狂いなく闇を切り裂く
Pierces the darkness without faltering.
迷いなんて吹き飛ばせばいい
Just blow away any hesitation,
この心が叫ぶ限り
As long as this heart cries out.
誰もひとり邪魔などさせない
I won't let anyone get in my way alone,
僅かに舞う無数の願いは
The countless wishes dancing faintly
この両手に積み募っていく
Pile up in these hands.
そらじゃあー！あー！
Sora-jaa! Aah!
すごい緊張した
I was so nervous.
改めて4周年おめでとう！ ありがとうー！
Happy 4th anniversary again! - Thank you!
もう4周年かぁ、や、すごい本当に本当に
Already 4 years... wow, really, truly.
4年目か、5年目のそらちゃん
4th year, or Sora-chan's 5th year.
そうだよ、もう5年目だよ、そらちゃん
That's right, already 5th year, Sora-chan.
めちゃくちゃ大先輩だ
Such a huge senior!
大先輩だ
A huge senior.
5歳だ
5 years old.
今日は呼んでくれてありがとう！
Thank you for inviting me today!
うちらもなんかこんな素敵なライブで、ソラアズで今日歌えるなんてめちゃくちゃ嬉しくて…
We're so happy to be able to sing together as SoraAZ in such a wonderful live today...
嬉しくて嬉しくて イェーイ！
So happy, so happy! Yay!
アズキッチともな、もう結構長いよね
AZKi-ch and I have known each other quite a long time.
ね、そうだよよね
Yeah, that's right.
もう何年、何年だろう、最初に、なんかソラアズでライブしたのが、でもなんか全然昨日のことのように
How many years... when was our first live as SoraAZ? It feels like just yesterday.
でもあれ3年前だったっけ？ そうだよね、きっと
It was 3 years ago? - Right, surely.
そんな、そう、最初ね、だから最初さ、なんか、ソラ、ソラ先輩って呼んでて
Back then, yeah, calling you "Sora-senpai".
今では考えられないの！今ソラ先輩って言われたら「えっ？」って
Now I can't imagine it! If you called me Sora-senpai now, I'd go "Huh?"
なんか、そう、ソラ先輩って呼んでて、で、なんか、その、ソラちゃんが、なんか「ソラちゃって呼んで」っていう
You called me Sora-senpai, and then Sora-chan said "Call me Sora-chan".
のを、なんか、その、ライブで、たしか言ってくれて、あ、そうだった、そうだったっけ
You mentioned it at a live show, ah right, was it?
それすら記憶に
Even that's in memory.
もう当たり前かのようにソラちゃんって呼んでいましても、そんな、そんなこともあったなと思って
I've naturally been calling you Sora-chan ever since, but I thought about how those things happened.
なんかそっから色々ね、一緒にほら歌ってみたとかね、そう
And since then, we've sung covers together and various things.
意外とだから、いっぱい色んな歌を歌ってるんだけど
Surprisingly we've sung lots of different songs.
今回の曲はね、あ、そう、この選曲は、私、歌いたかった
For this song... I wanted to sing it.
なんか、一緒に歌いたいなってなったときに、どうぜだったら2人で歌ったことがない曲にしようと思って
When we thought about wanting to sing together, I thought it should be a song we'd never sung as a duo.
で、考えてたの、で、実はその時にAZKiちゃんの歌とかを全部聞いて
And thought about it, and actually at that time I listened to all of AZKi's songs.
で、その時に「Lonely Merry-go-round」を歌ってる、それこう結構前だよね、これ
And when you sang "Lonely Merry-go-round", that was quite a while ago.
あ、そうだね、だいぶ前かも知れない
Ah right, might be quite a while ago.
のを見て、あ、かっこいい！あ、これだ
Seeing that, I thought "Ah, cool! Ah, this is it".
「これだ！」って、二人で歌いたいってなって
"This is it!" We wanted to sing this together,
ね、やっぱね、難しいじゃん、やっぱこの曲って
and you know, this song is really difficult, after all.
ねえ、そうだよね、難しいよね
Yeah, exactly. It's tough, right?
大丈夫かなと思ったから、その2人あって「あ、全然大丈夫！」みたいな
I wondered if we'd be okay, but when we tried it, we were like, "Ah, we're totally fine!"
さすがっ！で、で、でもだから
That's amazing! But, because...
そらちゃんが「歌いたい」って、なんかその
Sora-chan said she wanted to sing it, and like...
そらちゃんが歌ってるのを、なんか聴いたことなかったからめっちゃ
I'd never heard Sora-chan sing it before, so I was super...
なんか、その、なんか、めちゃ新鮮！「いいのかな？いいのかな？そんなそらちゃん見れちゃっていいのかな？」って思って
Like, wow, it's so fresh! I kept thinking, "Is it okay for me to see this side of Sora-chan?"
いやいやいやいや、今日楽しみにしてきた！
No, no, no, no! I came here looking forward to today!
いやあ、そうなんだよ、そうなんだよ、ねえ
Yeah, that's right, that's right, yeah!
だからね、本当に、なんか、こう、自分がやりたいことを、なんかみんなに叶えてもらえて、すごいね、そらちゃんの、そう
That's why, really, having everyone help make what I want to do come true, Sora-chan's... yeah.
すごいね、今日ね、ゲストもそうだし
Today's amazing, with the guests and everything—
もう曲選曲もそうだし、やりたいことをすごいやってるからさ、あります。
and the song choices, doing so much of what we want to do.
まだやり足りないことあるんじゃないですか？
Aren't there still things you haven't done yet?
あります！
There are!
と言うわけで？
So, with that being said...
と言うことで？
As in?
2人で歌っちゃおう！
Let's sing it together!
ここです！ここです！
Right here! Right here!
立ち位置です！立ち位置です！
Our positions! Our positions!
4人の立ち位置！
The four of us positions!
すごい、で、揺れてる、めちゃくちゃ揺れてる、何やってるの？
Amazing, and you're shaking, you're shaking so much, what are you doing?
いえーい！いーえー！いえーい！
Yay! Yay! Yay!
この動き難しい！
This movement is hard!
というわけで、私たちがやりたいもう一つのことっていうのが、私の曲を4人で歌いたいみたいな。
Anyway, another thing I wanted to do was have all four of us sing my song!
えー！えー！歌おうー！嬉しいですー！やったー！
Eh?! Let's sing it! We're so happy! Yay!
そう、なんかね、私の曲は、誰に行っても高い！高い、きつーって言われちゃう。
Yeah, so, my song, whoever I ask, it's high! "It's high, it's tough!" they say.
宣伝してる、宣伝してる。でも、歌います！
You're promoting it! But you'll sing it!
なんだけど、歌ってくれるということで、まあね、私の名前が、あの曲の中に出てくる曲なので。
But since you'll sing it, well, my name actually appears in the song lyrics, so...
なんと！あれじゃねえか！あれじゃねえかってことで、みんなで歌っていきたいと思いますので、よろしくお願いしまーす！
What?! No way! Since that's the case, we'd love for everyone to sing along!
イェーイ！イェーイ！イェーイ！イェーイ！
Yay! Yay! Yay! Yay!
それじゃあ、いきます！
Well then, here we go!
ドリームストーリー！イェーイ！
Dream Story! Yay!
いくよ！せーの！
Here we go! Ready, set!
イェーイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Yay! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
ふっと忘れてしまいたくなる 昨日のあの記憶のピースね
Wanting to just forget those pieces of yesterday's memories,
無くした利他はできそうもないけど上手く繋げばまた続きへ
you can't really replace them, but if you connect them well, it continues.
でも今は関係ないんだよ そんなことも忘れちゃうような
But right now none of that matters, it's a wondrous world
不思議な世界にアクセル全開で飛び込もう it's showtime!
where we can dive in at full throttle, it's showtime!
でもでも急ぎっぱなしは禁物です 急がば回れって言うくらいじゃん
But rushing all the time is a no-no, slow and steady wins the race, right?
だからたまにはゆっくり一休みしたら それじゃあちょっと早めのリズムで
So sometimes take a slow break, then let's pick up the tempo a bit,
止まれないぜ!
we can't stop now!
飛んでけ fly! (high!) 大きく息を吸ったら
Fly away, fly! (high!) Take a big breath,
ボクらの (wow!) ストーリー が今溢れ出るよ
our (wow!) story is now overflowing.
もっともっと大きくね 最初が肝心なんです!
Bigger and bigger, hey, the beginning is what counts!
はじめまして、こんにちは! せーのっ
Nice to meet you, hello! Ready, set—
ときのそら だよ! (yeah!)
It's Tokino Sora! (yeah!)
もいちど fly! (high!) そら 遠くまで 届け
Once more, fly! (high!) Sora, reach far away,
ドキドキ で (wow!) 奇想天外 に彩っていく dream☆story
with a pounding heart (wow!) coloring the extraordinary dream☆story!
やっぱ 1秒たりとも目を離さないで欲しいな
I really want you not to take your eyes off me for even a second,
瞬きもしてらんない ああ ほらね最高でしょ? イェー!
not even blinking. Ah, see? Isn't this the best? Yeah!
一歩進めば また後ろへ 見えない力が邪魔をしている
Take one step forward, then step back, an invisible force is getting in the way.
ジャンプしたりできたらいいけれど それも愛嬌 どうぞよろしく
It'd be nice if we could just jump, but that's charming too, nice to meet you.
でも今は関係ないんだよ 心響くリズムを辿れば
But right now none of that matters, if we follow the rhythm echoing in our hearts,
不思議な世界の続きのページで また出会えた destiny
we can meet again on the next page of this wondrous world, destiny.
もしもし 遅めのテンポも良いけれど 今はそんな場合じゃないわけじゃない?
Hello? A slow tempo is nice, but isn't this hardly the time for that?
だけど大丈夫 一息つけたのなら いちにのさんの合図で
But it's alright, if you've caught your breath, on the count of one, two, three—
いちにのさんで飛んでけ!
One, two, three, fly away!
行くよ
Here we go!
ふと 忘れおれてしまいしたくなる
I want to forget for a moment...
昨日のあの記憶のピース
yesterday's pieces of memory.
ねえ 無くしたりはできそうもないけど
Hey, we can't lose them,
うまく繋げばまた続きへ
if we connect them well, it keeps going.
でも 今は 関係ないんだよ
But right now, it doesn't matter!
そんなことも 忘れちゃいえるような 不思議な世界に
In this strange world where we forget such things,
アクセル全開で 飛び込もう it's show time
accelerator fully open, let's dive in, it's show time!
でも でも 急ぎっぱなしは禁物です
Wait, wait, rushing is forbidden!
いれば回ってるって言うくらいじゃん？
Doesn't it spin back around if you stay?
だから たまにはゆっくり一休みしたら
So sometimes let's take a slow break,
それじゃあちょっと早めのリズムで 止まら ねぇ ぞ
and then with a slightly quicker rhythm, don't stop, hey!
飛んでけ fly (high)
Fly high!
大きく息を吸ったら
When you take a big breath,
僕らの (wow) ストーリーが 今 溢れ出すよ
our story overflows!
もっともっと大きくね
Louder and louder,
最初が肝心なんです
the beginning is what matters most!
はじめまして こんにちは
Nice to meet you, hello!
せーの ときのそら だよ (yay)
Ready, it's Tokino Sora! (Yay!)
もう一度 fly (high)
Fly high once again!
空 遠くまで届け
Reach far into the sky!
ドキドキ で (wow)
With a pounding heart (wow),
奇想天外に 彩ってく dream story
adorned beyond imagination, a dream story!
やっぱ １秒たりとも
Even if we have just one second,
目を離さないでほしいな
we don't want you to look away,
瞬きもしてらんない
don't even blink!
あ ほらね 最高でしょ (yay)
Ah, see, isn't it the best? (Yay!)
一歩 進めば また後ろへ
Take a step forward, then back again.
見えない力が邪魔をしている
An unseen force is getting in the way.
ジャンプしたりできたらいいけれど
It would be great if we could just jump,
それも愛嬌 どうぞよろしく
but even that's charming, treat us well!
でも 今は 関係ないんだよ
Still, it doesn't matter right now!
心 響く リズムを 辿れば
Following the rhythm that echoes in our hearts,
不思議な正解の続きのページで また出会えた destiny
we meet a new destiny on the next page of wondrous answers.
もしも遥めのテンポもいいけど
A far-off tempo might be nice too,
今はそんな場合じゃないわけじゃない
but that's not the case right now, right?
だけど 大丈夫 一息つけたのならさ
Still, it's okay if you've caught your breath,
いちにのさんの合図で
on the count of one, two, three!
いちにのさん
One, two, three!
飛んでけ fly (high)
Fly high!
大きな声で叫んだら
Shouting with a big voice,
ぼくらの (wow) ストーリーが 今 繋がれてく
our story connects now!
もっともっと大きくね
Louder and louder,
ボリュームはマックスで
turn the volume to max!
はじめまして こんにちは
Nice to meet you, hello!
せーの ときのそら だよ (yay)
Ready, it's Tokino Sora! (Yay!)
もう一度 fly (high)
Fly high once again!
空 遠くまで響け
Let it echo far into the sky!
はちゃめちゃで (wow)
With a flurry (wow),
摩訶不思議にきらめいたんだ dream story
it shone in wondrous ways, a dream story!
やっぱ １秒たりとも 体感していたいよ
We want to experience it every single second,
クラクラしちゃうくらい あh だけど 最高じゃない
even if it makes us dizzy—ah, but it's the best!
はい というわけで 「Dream☆Story」を 歌って 歌いました！
Hey, everyone, we just sang "Dream☆Story",
やったー！ ヤッター！
Yay! We did it!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
難しかった 難しかったね
It was hard, wasn't it?
でも 楽しかった！
But it was fun!
よかったー
Yay!
いや 本当に 実はさ
Yeah, really. Actually, you know,
ここのメンバーってさ みんな
all of us members here,
アルバムも 出してるんだよ
we've all released albums, you know!
そうなんだ！
Is that right?!
そうなんです！
That's right!
なんと アルバム組じゃないですか？
Wait, this lineup is entirely album-releasing members, isn't it?
そうなんです！
That's right!
そう アルバム組といえばなんですが
Right, we're the album group, but actually...
なんだ？ なになに？
What? What? What?
私 ときのそら
Well, me, Tokino Sora...
どんっ
Boom!
えー サードアルバム「Re:Play」
My 3rd Album, "Re:Play",
カバーアルバムをですね 2021年11月に リリース決定しております！
has been decided for release in November 2021!
わあ おめでとうございます！
Yay! Congratulations!
ちょっと すみません なんか すみません
Oh, details are coming soon—sorry, sorry!
はい というわけで、あ、戻してくれて大丈夫です
Yes, so, wait, they put it back, it's fine.
というわけで ま、みんな、詳細も全然わかんないんですけど
So, everyone, well, I don't really know the details either,
ぜひ待っててくれると嬉しいです
but we'd be so happy if you look forward to it!
ねえ！
Right!
そうだよ これからね、3人はライブも
That's right, from now on, the three of us have live shows too—
あ そうなんです、我々は
Ah, that's right, we do!
アルバム組！
Album groups!
いや みんなね
Yeah, everyone,
こう 今回 呼んだ
you know, everyone we invited this time,
あの、やっぱ みんな たくさんアルバム出してて、歌うのが好きだ子たちが集まってるかなと思って
they've all put out lots of albums, and I thought,
このメンバーで歌いたかったんです
"I want to sing with these members."
好きです！
I love it!
やったー ありがとう そらちゃん
Yay, thank you! Sora-chan,
そらちゃんがさ、この なんかメンバーをね、誘ってくれて
you're the one who invited these members,
そう、それで今日 実現して
and now it's actually come true today,
なんか本当に なんかもう 尊い気分 本当に嬉しくて 嬉しいよ ありがとう
I just feel so honored and so happy!
ありがとうございます
Thank you!
あ、だから、あの、私ね、グループも作ったんですよ
So, we also made a new group!
これからね、これから末長く
From now on—wait, for a long time!
いろんなことしていきましょう いろんなことしていきましょう
Let's keep doing business together. Let's keep doing business together.
謙虚にしていこう
Let's keep it going respectfully.
そうなんです、そういう意味も込めてね
Right, incorporating that kind of meaning,
これからいっぱいね、こうみんなでね、仲良くさ、ら、いいんじゃないかなと思ってそのきっかけになればいいなと思って
we hope this can be a stepping stone to hang out all together a lot from now on,
今日は、うれしい、うれしい、うれしい、うれしい！
so today we're—yay! We're so happy!
はい、というわけでね 本当に素敵な3人が誘ったらみんな来てくれるって本当に奇跡だと思ってるから
And so, really, having these wonderful three members come when we invited them is truly a miracle,
本当にね、嬉しいなって思います 本当にありがとう ありがとう ありがとう
so I really feel so happy. Thank you so much!
いつでも呼んで、いつでも呼んで、いつでもライブしよう
Please invite us anytime! We'll do lives anytime!
じゃあ明日で、明日、あ、ちょっと
Then let's do it tomorrow! Tomorrow—well, tomorrow's a bit...
明日スケジュールが、あ、そう
Tomorrow's schedule is...
いつでもいいって言ったじゃん今！
We just said anytime!
まあね、そんなふうに言い合えるぐらい私達仲がいいので
Well, we get along so well like this, and our internal bond is great,
ぜひぜひみなさんもね、3人のチャンネルにも遊びに行ってほしいなって思います！
so we hope you'll all go visit the three of our channels too!
はーい！
Yes!
というわけで、今日は本当にありがとうございました！
So today, thank you so much!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
なんでもないよ
It's nothing.
5年目も止まらねえぞで
We won't stop in our 5th year either!
5年目も止まらねえぞ！
Our 5th year isn't stopping!
えでも最後の曲は みんな あれしよう 企画してくれて
For the last song, everyone planned something...
あ、な、見てるよ？ 見てる? 見てる？
Ah, w-are you watching? Watching? Watching?
やったやった！
Yay, yay!
嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
もうし、もう一人ぼっちになっちゃうのかと思った
I thought I was going to be all alone...
いるからね！うん、頑張ってね！
I'll be here! Yeah, do your best!
見張ってるよ 見張ってるの怖いけど、ちょっと分かった
I'm keeping watch! It's scary, but I kinda get it.
それでは 一旦ね、ていうか、まあステージに立つの、ここでそらさんには最後ということで
Well then, for now... or rather, since this is Sora-san's last time standing on stage...
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
頑張ってね！頑張って！
Do your best! Good luck!
いそげいそげしゅっしゅっしゅっ 私は水を飲みます
Hurry, hurry, shushushu... I'm going to drink some water.
前半すごいキチキチしました
The first half was really tight.
ここからは後半戦です
From here on is the second half.
て歌います。ここからは2曲連続で歌っていこうと思うので、ぜひ皆さん聞いてください
We'll sing two songs in a row from here, so please everyone listen.
それでは どうぞ。
And now, here it is.
沈むように溶けていくように
It's like we're sinking, it's like we're melting,
二人だけの空が広がる夜に
on that night where the sky stretched endlessly, just for the two of us.
「さよなら」だけだった その一言で全てが分かった
It was only a simple "goodbye," but it was all I needed to understand.
日が沈み出した空と君の姿 フェンス越しに重なっていた
The sinking sun and your figure were overlapping beyond the fence.
初めて会った日から 僕の心の全てを奪った
Ever since the first day we met, you stole all of my heart.
どこか儚い空気まと う君は 寂しい目をしていたんだ
Wrapped in some sort of fragile air, you had a lonely gaze.
いつだってチックタックと鳴 る世界で 何度だってさ
Again and again in the world always ringing with "tick-tocks,"
触れる心無い言葉うるさい声に 涙が零れそうでも
even if the tears seem about to spill over touching thoughtless words and irritating voices,
ありきたりな喜びきっと二人なら見つけられる
as long as we're together, I'm sure we can find an ordinary happiness.
騒がしい日々に笑えない君に 思い付く限り眩しい明日を
In the troubling days, for the never-smiling you, I give my utmost wishes for a dazzling tomorrow.
明けない夜に落ちていく前に 僕の体を掴んでほら
Before we fall in the never-ending night, come and take my hand.
忘れてしまいたくて閉じ込めた日々も 抱きしめた温もりで溶かすから
Even the days where you shut yourself away, wanting to forget, I'll melt with the warmth of my embrace,
怖くないよ いつか日が昇るまで 二人でいよう
so don't be afraid. Until the sun rises again someday, let's be together.
君にしか見えない 何かを見つめる君が嫌いだ
I hate it when you stare at the things only you can see,
見惚れているかのような恋するような そんな顔が嫌いだ
like you're captivated by it, or you're in love. I hate that expression.
信じてたいけど信じられないこと そんなのどうしたってきっと
The things I want to believe but I can't. No matter what I do, they'll pop up again and again.
これからだっていくつあって そのたび怒って泣いていくの
And every time I'll get angry and cry. Even so, someday we'll surely...
それでもきっといつかはきっと僕らはきっと 分かり合えるさ信じてるよ
understand each other; I believe that.
もう嫌だって疲れたんだって がむしゃらに差し伸べた僕の手を振り払う君
"I don't want this, I'm tired of it," I frantically reach for your hand, but you push my hands away.
もう嫌だって疲れたんだよなんて 本当は僕も言いたいんだ
"I don't want this, I'm tired of it," to tell the truth, I want to say that too.
騒がしい世界で何度も 君の為に用意した言葉 どれも届かない
In the world ringing with "tick-tock"s, again and again, none of the words I've prepared for you reach you.
「終わりにしたいたい」なんてさ 釣られて言葉にした時 君は初めて笑った
"I want to end it all," when I went along and said that, you smiled for the first time.
騒がしい日々に笑えなくなっていた 僕の目に映る君は綺麗だ
In the troubling days, I became unable to smile. You are truly beautiful in my eyes.
明けない夜に溢れた涙も 君の笑顔に溶けていく
The spilled-over tears in the never-ending night all dissolve into your smile.
変わらない日々に泣いていた僕を 君は優しく終わりへと誘う
In the never-changing days when I cried, you gently tempt me towards the end.
沈むように溶けていくように
It's like we're sinking, it's like we're melting,
二人だけの空が広がる夜に
on that night where the sky stretched endlessly,
その一言で全てが分かった
just for the two of us.
日が沈み出した空と君の姿
The sinking sun and your figure
フェンス越しに重なっていた
were overlapping beyond the fence.
初めて会った日から僕の心の全てを奪った
Ever since the first day we met, you stole all of my heart.
どこか儚い空気を纏う君は寂しそうな目をしていたんだ
Wrapped in some sort of fragile air, you had a lonely gaze.
鳴る世界で何回だってさ触れる心無い言葉うるさい声に
Again and again in the world always ringing with "tick-tocks,"
涙も零れそうでも
even if the tears seem about to spill,
ありきたりな喜びきっと二人なら見つけられる
as long as we're together, I'm sure we can find an ordinary happiness.
騒がしい日々に笑えない君に
In the troubling days, for the never-smiling you,
思い付く限り眩しい明日を
I give my utmost wishes for a dazzling tomorrow.
明けない夜に落ちていく前に僕の手を掴んでほら
Before we fall in the never-ending night, come and take my hand.
忘れてしまいたくて閉じ込めた日々も
Even the days where you shut yourself away, wanting to forget,
抱きしめた温もりで溶かすから
I'll melt with the warmth of my embrace,
怖くないよいつか日が昇るまで二人でいよう
so don't be afraid. Until the sun rises again someday,
君にしか見えない何を見つめる君が嫌いだ
let's be together.
見惚れているかのような恋をするようなそんな顔が嫌いだ
Like you're captivated by it, or you're in love—I hate that expression.
信じていたいたいけど信じられないことそんなたびに怒って泣いていくの
The things I want to believe but I can't no matter what I do,
それでもきっといつかはきっと僕らはきっと分かり合えるさ信じてるよ
they'll pop up again and again from now on.
もういっそ「一緒ランド」作りましょ
We might as well just create our "togetherland,"
君とマッチアップ乗っかってって
hopping on this match-up with you.
「構ってもっと足りないの」
"Gimme more attention. It's not enough."
歌え思い出染み付いた嫉妬のstyle
Sing it—the style of jealousy steeped in memories.
代わる代わる傷付けては
We took our turns to hurt each other
「もうしない」って嘘で仲直りごっこだ
only to make a show of reconciliation,
勘違いの騙し合い 目を見ればすぐに分かるってバカみたい
lying about how we "won't do it anymore."
“妄想”に好きって言うほどこの愛は腐ってるんだよ
"This love has become so rotten to the point that I can profess my love to this 'delusion.'
早く気付いてくれないと
Just realize it already.
アンドロイドガールおかしくなっちゃった
Android girl, I've gone out of my mind.
僕だけのものになった君は“誰”なの？
You've become mine and mine alone, but "who" exactly are you?
ずっとずっと信じてきたのにさ
And to think I've trusted you all this time, all this time.
アンドロイドガール想いはなんだっけ
Android girl, what was my feeling for you again?
君とのキスが痛くて息を閉じたのずっとずっと
The kiss we shared hurt so badly, I had to shut down my breath.
何度愛を再起動したって
No matter how many times I reboot this love,
ちょっとだって変われやしないよ
it can't possibly change, not even by a little bit.
「あぁ可愛いねどうしてくれないよう」
"Gosh, how adorable—whatever am I gonna do with you?"
もう疲れたドキドキさせるお世辞のresize
I've had enough of that—gotta resize those heart-fluttering compliments.
鬱陶しい鬱陶しいの併合罪
Annoying, annoying concurrent offences—
どう期待していいのか分からなくなったよ
I don't even know what I'm supposed to hope for anymore.
エンドロールはまだですか
Is it still not time for the end credits yet?
どこにいても一緒だなんてマジで痛い
"We're always together, no matter where"? That's seriously cringy.
“感傷”に浸っていいかな あの頃を願っていいかな
Is it okay if I were to indulge myself in "sentimentalism"?
アリかナシか教えてよ
Can I wish for those days to come back? Yes or no? Tell me.
アンドロイドガールおかしくなっちゃった
Android girl, I've gone out of my mind.
君だけのものになった“僕”が好きなの？
Do you love "me," now that I've become yours and yours alone?
ずっとずっと騙してきたんだね
Looks like you've deceived me all this time, all this time.
アンドロイドガール想いはなんだっけ
Android girl, what was my feeling for you again?
錆び憑いた腕で何度僕を求めた？ずっとずっと
How many times did you seek me out, with those rust-consumed arms?
アンドロイドガールおかしくなっちゃった
Android girl, I've gone out of my mind.
僕だけのものになった君は“誰”なの？
You've become mine and mine alone, but "who" exactly are you?
ずっとずっと信じてきたのにさ
And to think I've trusted you all this time, all this time.
アンドロイドガール想いはなんだっけ
Android girl, what was my feeling for you again?
君とのキスが痛くて息を閉じたのずっとずっと
The kiss we shared hurt so badly, I had to shut down my breath.
我儘が離れない君だけは許さない
I can't shake off my selfishness—never shall I forgive you.
アンドロイドガールおかしくなっちゃった
Android girl, I've gone out of my mind.
君だけのものになった“僕”が好きなの？
Do you love "me," now that I've become yours and yours alone?
ずっとずっと騙してきたんだね
Looks like you've deceived me all this time, all this time.
アンドロイドガール想いはなんだっけ
Android girl, what was my feeling for you again?
錆び憑いた腕で何度僕を求めた？ずっとずっと
How many times did you seek me out, with those rust-consumed arms?
何度愛を再起動したって
No matter how many times I reboot this love,
ちょっとだって変われやしないよ
it can't possibly change, not even by a little bit.
アンドロイドガールおかしくなっちゃった
Android girl, I've gone out of my mind.
僕だけのものになった君は“誰”なの？
You've become mine and mine alone, but "who" exactly are you?
ずっとずっと信じてきたのにさ
And to think I've trusted you all this time, all this time.
アンドロイドガール想いはなんだっけ
Android girl, what was my feeling for you again?
君とのキスが痛くて息を閉じたのずっとずっと
The kiss we shared hurt so badly, I had to shut down my breath.
何度愛を再起動したって
No matter how many times I reboot this love,
ちょっとだめだが離れない
it can't possibly change, not even by a little bit.
君だけは許さない！
You alone I can never forgive!
アンドロイドガールおかしくなっちゃった
Android girl, I've gone out of my mind.
君だけのものになった僕が好きなの？ずっとずっと
You've become mine and mine alone, but "who" exactly are you?
ずっと噂してきたんだね
And to think I've trusted you all this time, all this time.
アンドロイドガール想いはなんだっけ
Android girl, what was my feeling for you again?
錆び付いた腕で何度も僕を求めた？ずっとずっと
How many times did you seek me out, with those rust-consumed arms?
何度愛を再起動したって
No matter how many times I reboot this love,
ちょっとだって変われやしないよ何度愛を再起動したって
it can't possibly change, not even by a little bit.
ちょっとだって変われやしないよ
Android girl, I've gone out of my mind.
はい、というわけで
So... yeah.
生で歌うのは初めてで
It's my first time singing live,
めちゃくちゃ緊張してたんですけど、いかがだったでしょうか？
and I was super nervous, but I wonder how it was?
うん。
Mm.
今日はね、えっと、いま
Today, um, well, I've—
今までよりも、
Unlike the ones before,
すごく なんか5年目に入るということで、
since it's entering the fifth year,
なんか いつもと違う 緊張感が
I felt a tension different from usual,
あったかなと思うんですけども。
I think.
そんな時にね、
And at that time,
3人に助けてもらって、
with the three of them helping me,
すごくすごく なんか 自分の中で くやしいところもいっぱいあるんですけど、
even though I have a lot of frustrating feelings inside,
とっても楽しい!
it's so much fun!
4周年ライブになったと思います。
I think it's become a 4th anniversary live.
本当にありがとうございます!
Thank you so much!
えー5年目ということでね、これから5年目に入っていく、すごいキリの良い数ではあるんですけども、
As we enter the 5th year, it's a very clear-cut milestone,
まだまだ私にとってはもうあっという間に過ぎた時期でしたし、
but for me, it feels like it went by in the blink of an eye,
もっともっとみんなと頑張っていきたいなと思ってますし、
and I want to work even harder with everyone.
これからもみんなとずっとずっと歩いていきたいなって私思ってます!
I truly believe I want to keep walking side by side with everyone from now on!
これからも私たちについてきてくれますか?
Will you keep walking alongside us from now on too?
ついてきてくれますか?
Will you come with us?
これからもどうぞ
Please continue to support us from now on as well.
よろしくお願いします!
Thank you very much!
あー、緊張ほぐれ…今更緊張ほぐれちゃった。
Oh, I'm getting all disheveled.
I'm getting all disheveled just now.
これは、うん、多分緊張してなかった、みんな私の緊張伝わっちゃってたかな。
I guess I wasn't that nervous, or maybe everyone's tension had already rubbed off on me.
いやでもなんか、ね、緊張してても楽しめればいいかなって思って、
Yeah, but you know, even if you're nervous, you can still enjoy it,
ま、始まる前はね、ちょっとね、あ、なんか緊張しすぎて調子が、調子があってね、今日久しぶりに言ってたんですけど、
so before it started, I was saying today for the first time in a while,
始まっちゃうとね、なんてことないって。
once it starts, there's no such thing!
こんなにたくさんの人が待っててくれるんだったら、私頑張れるなって思えましたし、
When so many people are waiting for me, I realize I can do my best,
やっぱね、一緒に歌うっていうのがね、とっても楽しかったです!
and you know, singing together with everyone is just so much fun!
でも最後はさ、やっぱりさ、あこちらこそよろしくお願いします、いやこちらこそ楽しみの一番いいよね、ね、そうだよね。
And as for the ending, well, of course, the best part of anticipation is—yeah, right?
止まんないんじゃぞ、止まらねぇぞということでね。
It's not going to stop, it's not going to stop!
最後 私の誕生日にちょっと出した曲、まなんかすごいね、ぬーぬーんっていっぱい言う曲なんですけども、
And finally, a song I released around my birthday—it's a song with a lot of "nu-nu-nus,"
それをね、みんなで行っていこうかなと思います。
and I thought we'd all sing it together.
みんなが言うわけじゃなくて私が歌うんだけど、みんなにぬーぬって言ってほしい。
Not that everyone says it, I'm the one singing, but I want everyone to say "nu-nu-nu."
練習だよ。
Let's practice!
ぬーぬぬぬぬぬぬぬぬぬぬぬ!はい!言えたかな?あ、みんなぬーぬん言ってくれてますね。ありがとうございます!
Did you manage it? Ah, everyone's saying "nu-nu-nu"! Thank you so much!
ていうわけで、最後はこの曲で締めたいと思います。
So, let's close with this song!
雲晴れ!
KumoHurray!
(ぬーぬんぬん！ぬーぬん！ぬーぬんぬん！ぬーぬぬぬぬ)
Nu-nu-nu-nu, nu-nu-nu!
さあ！前へ 進め！)
Now, let's move forward!
ふわふ和と
Fluffy and light,
リズムに合せて
matching the rhythm,
ステップ踏んでこう
let's take a step,
どこまでもう羽ばたいていけそう さあ
so we can soar anywhere!
ドキドキ (ドキドキ)
Doki-doki (doki-doki),
ワクワク (ワクワク)
Waku-waku (waku-waku),
胸が高鳴るよ
my heart is pounding!
この想いはもう止まらない
This feeling won't stop anymore!
みんな元気にいこうよ
Let's all go with high spirits,
大きな声出して叫ぼう!
shouting out loud!
心が軽くなっていくからさ
Because our hearts grow lighter,
君の心は曇りのち晴れ わって
your cloudy heart will turn to clear,
虹をかけるよ
and we'll paint a rainbow!
胸を張って今を進もう
Walk proudly into the present,
星のように輝いて
shining like a star!
(ぬーぬんぬんっ)
(Nu-nu-nu!)
呼吸を合わせて
Aligning our breath,
気持ち重ねていこ
let's share our feelings.
いたずらもし合えたらいいよね!
Mischief is fine if we share a laugh!
じゃあ
Now then,
敵だね? (ヤメテヨー)
an enemy? (Stop it!)
うそだよ! (そっかー)
No way! (Is that so?)
ささやかな会話で
In our casual conversations,
私たちは今わかりあう
we understand each other now.
越えていこう
Let's push beyond!
あのときのそらよりももっと遠くまで
Going even further than Tokino Sora,
みんなを追い置いていかないからね
we can't leave anyone behind, so come on!
さあ、止まれないぜ
Now, there's no stopping us!
うあのそらになれないで歩けたなら ゆっくりでも道はできる
Even if we can't be like Sora-chan, if we walk step by step,
ゆっくりでも道はできる
we can carve out a path.
夢の色を描いて
Painting the colors of our dreams,
曇りがちな気分も
even gloomy moods—
ちょっと目線を変えたなら
if we just change our perspective a bit,
心晴れ晴れ 明るくなれるかもよ?
might brighten right up!
1人じゃないよ
You're not alone!
不安になったらここに来ればいいよ
If you feel anxious, just come here,
私はずっと待っているからね
because I'll always be waiting.
負けてもいい
It's okay to stumble;
がんばってきたことは無駄じゃないから
all your hard work was never in vain.
胸を張って今を生こう
Live the present with pride,
星のように輝いて
shining like a star!
(ぬーぬんぬん！ぬーぬん！ぬーぬんぬん！ぬーぬぬぬぬ)
(Nu-nu-nu-nu, nu-nu-nu!)
さあ！前へ 進め！)
Now, let's move forward!
一度きりの 私の物語は
My once-in-a-lifetime story
運命を超えて 煌めくんだ
shines brightly, transcending destiny.
行こう
Let's go.
ねえ 私より私のことを
Nee, you understand me better
わかってくれる キミの存在が
than I know myself—
怯えで泣き虫な心に
your presence brought courage as magic
勇気と言う魔法をかけたの
to my timid, crybaby heart.
チクタク
Tick-tock,
時計の針だけが進む
only the clock hands move forward.
立ち止まってちゃダメだ
Standing still won't do.
ソラ 転び八起きがお決まりでしょ
Sora, falling and getting up is the routine, right?
一つ一つ重ねてきた
One by one, piling them up,
大切なアルバムをめくるように
like turning the pages of a precious album,
一つ一つ叶えてきた 今日までを
one by one, making dreams come true up to today,
その全てにキミがいてくれた
you were there for all of it.
終わりのない夢を ずっとずっとずっとずっと
An endless dream, always, always, always, always
追いかけて行こう 行こう
let's chase it, let's go.
ねえ ここで笑い合えることが 何より大事な真実
Nee, being able to smile together here is the truest thing of all.
チクタク
Tick-tock,
イタズラなハートが痛む
a mischievous heart aches.
空回り 空回り
Spinning in circles, spinning in circles,
思考回路フル回転で よーいどん
mind running at full speed, ready, set, go!
泣いて泣いて泣いた夜も
Even nights I cried and cried and cried
大切な人生のストーリーだから
are part of life's precious story,
夢を夢で終わらせたくないんだ
so I don't want to end my dream just as a dream.
まだ見ぬ景色を見に行こうよ
Let's go see scenery we haven't seen yet!
もっともっとかがやいて
Shining brighter and brighter,
高く高く飛び立とう
flying higher and higher,
奇跡さえも越えて
surpassing even miracles.
一つ一つ重ねてきた
One by one, piling them up,
未来地図のページをめくるように
like turning the pages of a future map,
一つ一つ叶えてきた 今日までを
one by one, making dreams come true up to today,
その全てにキミがいてくれた
you were there for all of it.
最後に、ときのそらの告知タイムです！
Lastly, here is an announcement time from Tokino Sora!
ときのそら 活動四周年記念グッズ 発売決定！
Tokino Sora 4th Anniversary Goods release decided!
BIGメガネ置きアクリルスタンドと 活動四周年記念ピンバッチを作りました！
We made a BIG glasses-holder acrylic stand and 4th Anniversary pin badge!
詳細はこちら！
Details are here!
イラストは、おるだん先生です。私に好きなメガネをかけて楽しんでね！
Illustration is by Orudan-sensei. Enjoy putting your favorite glasses on her!
ピンバッチはこちら！アンティーク調のデザインの素敵なピンバッチです。
The pin badge is here! It's a wonderful pin badge with an antique design.
22時から販売開始！ぜひ皆さん購入してね！
Sales start at 22:00! Everyone, please be sure to buy them!
そして、もう今日の昼には発表されていたいそうなのですが、私ときのそらのねんどろいどが受注開始しています！
And, though it was probably announced earlier today, pre-orders for my Nendoroid have started!
笑顔やじと目、あんこともついてきます！
It comes with smiling and smug face plates, as well as Ankimo!
そらに懐かしの猫耳や猫手があったりマイクもつてもあるのでこの機会を逃すと手に入らないよ！
Sora also has nostalgic cat ears, cat paws, and a mic, so if you miss this chance you won't get them!
是非みんな予約してね！合わせて
Everyone, please be sure to pre-order! Also,
さっきも告知したとおりカバーアルバムも現在制作中です！
as announced earlier, a cover album is currently in production!
タイトルは「Re:Play」2021年11月リリース予定！
Title is "Re:Play", scheduled for release in November 2021!
収録楽曲などは今後の情報をお待ちください！
Please look forward to future info regarding tracklist and more!
さらに、なんとなんとこの後9月8日水曜日0時より4周年を記念して、過去のアルバムの未配信楽曲を配信にてリリースします！
Furthermore, what's more, starting at midnight on Wednesday, September 8th, to commemorate the 4th anniversary, we will release previously undelivered tracks from past albums via streaming!
「Dreaming!」の初回盤特典にシークレットトラックで収録された「シーソーゲーム」、「パラレルタイム」の初回限定版特典に収録された「コトバ風」「ワンダーランド」「ステップ&ゴー」のアコースティックバージョン、
('Seesaw Game' included as a secret track on 'Dreaming!', acoustic versions of 'Kotoba Kaze', 'Wonderland', 'Step & Go' included on 'Parallel Time' limited edition,)
私のチャンネルで投稿した「好き、泣いちゃいそうだ」のアコースティック音源の全5曲です！
(and acoustic versions of 'Suki, Naicha Sou da' posted on my channel—all 5 songs!)
告知は以上だよ！今日は配信見に来くれてありがとう！
That's all for announcements! Thank you for coming to watch the stream today!